ok so I think it's 8:30 good morning
好的，我想是8:30早上好
everybody I'm happy that so many of you
每个人我都很高兴你们这么多
could make it to the first morning
可以到第一天早上
session I hope it will be interesting
会议我希望这会很有趣
enough for you so you really can wake up
对你来说足够了，所以你真的可以醒来
so I was speaking today about analyzing
所以我今天说的是关于分析
hot spot crashes
热点崩溃
my name is focusing moniece I'm working
我的名字叫莫妮丝，我在工作
for sa P in the AP JVM team we are doing
对于AP JVM团队中的sa P，我们正在做
our own s AP Java Virtual Machine which
我们自己的AP Java虚拟机
is based on a hot spot a licensed
基于热点
version of hot spot at the same time we
同时我们的热点版本
are also working heavily in the open JDK
在开放的JDK中也很忙
we are the maintainer and contributors
我们是维护者和贡献者
of the PowerPC ax and s/390 port and we
PowerPC斧头和s / 390端口，我们
are also in the Java Executive Committee
也在Java执行委员会中
ok so let's get started with the talk if
好吧，让我们开始谈谈
there are any questions please ask if
有什么问题请问
they are quick it will try to answer
他们很快就会尝试回答
them if not we can do it after the talk
如果没有他们，我们可以在谈话后做
so all the examples I have in this talk
所以我在这次演讲中的所有例子
and the slides themselves are on github
幻灯片本身在github上
so if you want to take pictures you can
因此，如果您想拍照，可以
take picture of this slide I will show
拍这张幻灯片的照片，我将展示
you slide once again
你再滑一次
at the end of the talk so you will have
在演讲结束时，您将拥有
one more chance to get it ok so
再有一次机会就可以了
everybody ready so what's a hot spot
每个人都准备好了，什么是热点
crash well it's actually a fatal error
崩溃好了，这实际上是一个致命错误
or situation which from which we cannot
或我们无法做到的情况
recover it's not compared to an
恢复它不与
exception for example which we can
例如我们可以例外
handle an exception and or an unhandled
处理异常和/或未处理
exception shows error in your own
异常显示您自己的错误
program in the application while a hot
在应用程序中编程时很热
spot crash or VM crash shows an error in
点崩溃或VM崩溃显示错误
the in the virtual machine itself which
在虚拟机本身中
should not happen so the only thing we
不应该发生，所以我们唯一的事情
can do as I say it's an unrecoverable
可以做到，我说这是无法恢复的
error the only thing we can do is we can
错误我们唯一能做的就是
try to gather as much information as
尝试收集尽可能多的信息
possible from the crash to analyze it to
可能从崩溃中分析出来
find the root cause and to prevent it
找到根本原因并加以预防
the next time so to bring everybody up
下次再带大家
on the same line just a very quick brief
在同一行上只是一个非常简短的摘要
introduction about a hotspot VM so on
关于热点VM的介绍等
the very base we have two CPUs I won't
最基本的是我们有两个CPU
go into CPUs today during
今天要进入CPU
my last 12 years I was working on hot
我过去的12年中一直在从事热门工作
spot we find some cpu errors as well but
当场我们也发现一些CPU错误，但是
I won't go into this topic today so on
我今天不会讨论这个话题
the base we have C++ code we have the
我们有C ++代码的基础
Java launcher we have different Java
Java启动器，我们有不同的Java
libraries Lib Java which is the native
库Lib Java是原生的
part of the class library we have the
类库的一部分，我们有
system C libraries which is all C code
系统C库都是C代码
or in memory then the biggest part is
或记忆中最大的部分是
obviously the hotspot itself the virtual
显然，热点本身就是虚拟的
machine itself which is in the Lib JVM
Lib JVM中的计算机本身
shared library it consists of the
共享库包含
runtime then GC and to JIT compilers if
运行时，然后使用GC和JIT编译器（如果有）
you're using the server version of the
您正在使用的服务器版本
hotspot which is the default today this
热点，这是今天的默认值
is also written in C++ then on the next
也用C ++编写，接下来
level we have generated code so this is
级别，我们已经生成了代码，所以这是
one of the major problems when it comes
遇到的主要问题之一
to debugging and analyzing hotspot
调试和分析热点
errors that we have to deal a lot with
我们必须处理的错误
generated code where native debugger
生成本地调试器的代码
cannot help us very much so first of all
不能对我们有很大帮助，所以首先
the interpreter itself is generated I
解释器本身是生成的
will show you a quick example in one of
将向您展示一个简单的例子
the following slides how this looks like
以下幻灯片看起来像
then we have various tabs which is kind
然后我们有各种选项卡
of glue code between the native C code
本地C代码之间的粘合代码
and the generated compiler just in time
以及及时生成的编译器
compiled code we have C 1 compiled
我们有C 1的已编译代码
method C 2 compiled method so by the way
方法C 2编译方法如此
C 1 is the client compilers it - is
C 1是客户端编译器-是
there a server compiler which runs
有一个服务器编译器运行
slower but generates by the code and
速度较慢，但​​由代码和
recently we have ahead of time compiled
最近我们提前编译了
message which also appear in the code
消息也出现在代码中
cache now and finally we have the data
现在缓存，最后我们有了数据
of our program so we have the Java
我们的程序，所以我们有Java
objects in the Java heap we have the
Java堆中的对象
classes themselves which today live in
自己上课，今天住在
the meta space previously they lived in
他们以前居住的元空间
a part of the heap the circled term
带圆圈的术语是堆的一部分
generation but it was removed with in
代，但已在中删除
Java 8 and we still the VM still uses a
Java 8，我们仍然在VM仍使用
considerable part of C heap so this is
C堆的相当一部分，所以这是
also something many people are not aware
还有很多人不知道的事情
of
的
they configure the virtual machine let's
他们配置虚拟机，让我们
say with 8 gigabyte and then they wonder
说8 GB，然后他们想知道
why it uses 12 so for example a
为什么要使用12，例如
just-in-time compiler can very well use
即时编译器可以很好地使用
up to a gigabyte for compiling a very
高达一个千兆字节，用于编译一个非常
large method and depending on the
大方法，并取决于
hardware you are running on you have a
您正在运行的硬件有一个
lot of threads running
很多线程正在运行
even if you start just the hello world
即使您只是开始打招呼的世界
program a hotspot VM will today start at
对热点VM进行编程，今天将开始于
least 10 threads we have the VM straight
我们至少有10个线程
which does some bookkeeping you have a
你有一些簿记
GCS write various number of uses right
GCS编写各种使用权
depending of the course you have various
根据课程的不同
number of JIT threads and they all also
JIT线程数，它们也都
of course need memory and when they
当然需要记忆，当他们
while they are running they also consume
他们在跑步时也会消耗
Sahib and finally we have the
Sahib，最后我们有了
application threads the Java threads and
应用程序线程Java线程和
these Java threads they execute the code
这些Java线程执行代码
from here so they are started by the
从这里开始，所以他们由
launch art and they jump into the
发射艺术品，他们跳进了
runtime they execute some interpreter
运行时，他们执行一些解释器
code to execute maybe just in time
要及时执行的代码
compile code and so on and during this
编译代码等等，在此期间
talk we will see which places we can
交谈，我们将看到可以在哪些地方
crash and how we can detect that and
崩溃以及我们如何检测到
hopefully fix it so we have a very small
希望解决它，所以我们有一个很小的
crash example so who of you has seen
崩溃的例子，所以你们当中谁见过
this before when he was running a java
这是在他运行Java之前
application so may probably a lot of you
应用程序，所以可能很多人
that's why we're here ok so what does
这就是为什么我们在这里还可以，所以
this say us so first of all it gives a
这说了我们，所以首先
short brief summary what happens so in
简短的摘要总结
this this case the segmentation fault
这种情况下分割错误
happened at this program counter it
发生在这个程序柜台
tells us the function which was on top
告诉我们最上面的功能
of the stack when the error happened so
错误发生时的堆栈数量
in this case it was in the Lib JVM so in
在这种情况下，它在Lib JVM中，所以在
the virtual machine itself it was a
虚拟机本身是
memory access function it tells us where
内存访问功能告诉我们在哪里
the core file was written to and it also
核心文件已写入，并且
tells us where the hotspot error file
告诉我们热点错误文件在哪里
was written to so this hotspot error
被写到这个热点错误
file is actually the data we will look
文件实际上是我们将要查看的数据
at most during this talk because it
最多在这次谈话中，因为
contains a lot of useful information so
包含很多有用的信息，所以
there are some Cavett's when you on run
跑步时有一些卡维特
with you limit minus c 0 so core 5 0 no
你限制负c 0所以核心5 0否
core 5 will be produced so usually it
通常会生产核心5
can be very helpful to have core files
拥有核心文件可能会非常有帮助
as we will see so at least when you run
正如我们将至少在您运行时看到的那样
into a problem and want to reproduce it
陷入问题并想重现
you should set your limit minus c 2
您应该将极限值设置为c 2
unlimited so you get a core file also
无限，因此您也可以获得核心文件
gnu/linux systems like a bun too even if
gnu / linux系统也像包子一样，即使
you settle in
你安顿下来
- unlimited qualifies won't be created
-无限资格将不会被创建
in your file system but they will be
在您的文件系统中，但它们将
piped to a system application like
通过管道传输到系统应用程序，例如
airport and you won't see them so you
机场，你不会看到他们，所以你
may have to configure this in proxies
可能必须在代理中进行配置
comic or pattern or depending on your
漫画或图案，或取决于您
system this may be a different file but
系统这可能是一个不同的文件，但
you may have to configure the core
您可能必须配置核心
pattern to a file on your file system
模式到文件系统上的文件
and not to to a pipe somewhere here to a
而不是到这里某处的管道
service program okay so how did I
服务程序还可以，我该怎么办
produce this crash it's actually very
造成这种崩溃实际上是非常
simple by using unsafe you know you
简单地使用不安全的方法，您就会知道
shouldn't use unsafe because as the name
不应该使用不安全的名称，因为
says it's unsafe but it's very handy for
说这是不安全的，但是对于
producing crashes so actually what we do
导致崩溃，所以实际上我们在做什么
here is I just define a method crash and
这是我只是定义一个方法崩溃和
it uses unsafe to write a value X to
它使用不安全的值X写入
address 99 so address 99 is usually not
地址99，因此地址99通常不是
accessible and we call crash is 42 and
可访问性，我们称崩溃为42，
write it to others 99 it is crashes the
写给别人99它崩溃了
program so let's see how that's what
程序，所以让我们看看这是怎么回事
error file looks in this case so on top
错误文件在这种情况下看起来是这样
of the hotspot error file we have a
热点错误文件中，我们有一个
summary
摘要
it contains the exact command line this
它包含确切的命令行
already can be very useful when you for
当您为
example get what's whatever file from
例子从什么得到什么文件
your client this can be useful to see
您的客户，这很有用
what what you run it contains quite
您所运行的内容包含
detailed information about the CPU the
有关CPU的详细信息
hardware which was used both operating
同时使用的硬件
system which was used and how long the
使用的系统以及多长时间
program did run in our case this was
程序确实在我们的情况下运行，这是
just a second of course but we often get
当然只有一秒钟，但我们经常得到
crash files from clients which run for
从运行的客户端崩溃文件
weeks or even months so you see if a
数周甚至数月，以便您查看是否
problem appears after a few months
几个月后出现问题
that's not easy to reproduce usually
通常不容易复制
usually so you better have all the
通常，所以您最好拥有所有
information you want in this error file
您在此错误文件中需要的信息
or in the core file if you have one
或在核心文件中（如果您有一个）
because you won't get a second chance
因为你不会再有机会
ok let's dig deeper into the hot spot
好的，让我们深入研究热点
error file as next section is the Java
错误文件，因为下一部分是Java
stack trace it contains all the Java
堆栈跟踪它包含所有Java
stack frames which were on the stack
堆栈中的堆栈帧
when the error occurred and we see we
当错误发生时，我们看到我们
called our crash program and this called
叫我们的崩溃程序，这个叫
unsafe then according to JDK misc and
然后根据JDK misc不安全
thermal unsafe which is in JDK 9 simply
JDK 9中的热不安全
datian of unsafe and then called put in
不安全的大田，然后叫入
but that's just the java frames when you
但这只是当您使用Java框架时
if you remember in the beginning we saw
如果你还记得一开始
that we actually crashed in a c function
我们实际上崩溃了交流功能
which is in lip JVM so the next section
这是在嘴唇JVM中，所以下一部分
what's what arrow fire contains the so
箭火包含什么
called native or Mixtec trace which
称为本机或Mixtec跟踪
contains all the actual frames which
包含所有实际帧
have been on the stack and here you can
已经在堆栈上，在这里您可以
see we start with sleepy sweat starts
看到我们从昏昏欲睡的汗水开始
right then the Java main in the drama
就在这出戏中的Java主角
launcher which in leap jli then we go
在飞跃jli然后我们去的发射器
through Jane I call static and so on all
通过简我称静态等等
the stack up finally we arrive our Java
最终我们到达了Java
methods and the last Java matter tend to
方法和最后的Java问题趋向于
put it unsafe put in course into native
把它不安全地放在本地
code so unsafe put it it's the
如此不安全的代码
implementation of this this is declared
此声明的实现
negative in Java and this then calls
Java中的负数，然后调用
into the Lib JDM itself where we come to
进入Lib JDM本身
the actual method where the crash
崩溃的实际方法
occurred yes so it's just an animation
发生了，所以它只是一个动画
of what I showed you it was not true I
我告诉你的那件事不是真的
will have a laser pointer so to come
将有一个激光笔，以便未来
back to our overview so we crashed in
回到我们的概述，所以我们坠毁了
the runtime while executing runtime code
执行运行时代码时的运行时
in a Java thread so that was easy so
在Java线程中很容易
digging further into the hotspot error
进一步研究热点错误
file there is a section which contains
文件中有一个包含
order which registers the value of the
记录该值的订单
registers when the VM crashed and as you
在VM崩溃时以及在您注册时进行注册
can see the register ax contained the
可以看到包含
value 42 this was actually the way we
值42这实际上是我们的方式
were writing to the address 99 if you
正在写地址99
remember and address that register dxdx
记住并寻址该寄存器dxdx
contains the address but this is a
包含地址，但这是一个
register to memory mapping it's not
注册到内存映射不是
actually just the pure register values
实际上只是纯寄存器值
as you can see here while writing this
正如您在撰写本文时所看到的
hotspot error file the VM tries to make
VM尝试制作的热点错误文件
sense of these values and for example
这些价值观的意义，例如
the register RBX contained a strange hex
寄存器RBX包含一个奇怪的十六进制
value which we in knew what it is but
我们知道它是什么的价值，但是
the VM could find out that this is
虚拟机可以发现这是
actually a pointer to the put int method
实际上是一个指向put int方法的指针
so
所以
for these other values the VM couldn't
对于这些其他值，虚拟机无法
find out or actually this one is
找出或实际上这是
pointing into the stack but there is no
指向堆栈，但没有
more information about it and finally we
关于它的更多信息，最后我们
see it at the top of the page we see
在我们看到的页面顶部看到它
this strange arrow it says error
这个奇怪的箭头说错误
occurred during error reporting so while
在错误报告期间发生
the VM was writing the error file it was
VM正在写入错误文件
trying to make sense of the values
试图理解价值观
contained in the register it's run into
包含在它运行的寄存器中
another problem probably another
另一个问题可能是另一个
segmentation fault because as I told you
细分错误，因为我告诉过您
we are in an inconsistent state the VM
我们处于不一致状态的虚拟机
cannot be sure about all the values in
无法确定中的所有值
the register if there are objects or
如果有物件则登记
where they are pointing to but it tries
他们指向的地方，但尝试
to find it out and during this procedure
找出来，并在此过程中
it may run into another problem but
它可能会遇到另一个问题，但
there is a very sophisticated algorithms
有一个非常复杂的算法
in the hot spot which catch this
在抓住这个的热点
segmentation faults ignore them and
分段错误将其忽略，并且
tries to go forward inverting the
尝试向前反转
hotspot FS to provide as much
热点FS提供尽可能多的
information as possible so after this
信息，所以在此之后
error this section will be closed the
错误，本节将被关闭
register mapping but the hotspot writing
注册映射，但热点写作
will continue with the next section and
下一节将继续
actually the next section is the pure
实际上下一部分是纯
register values and here you saw it
注册值，在这里您看到了
couldn't make sense of register R 9 so
无法理解寄存器R 9，所以
here we see register R 9 has this value
在这里我们看到寄存器R 9具有该值
and this happened to point into the heap
而这恰好指向堆
but it didn't really point at the
但这并没有真正指向
beginning of an object so while the the
对象的开始，因此
VM wanted to print out the type of the
VM想要打印出
object but because it just happened to
对象，但因为它刚发生
point into heap but not at the beginning
指向堆，但不在开始
of an object it crashed while followed
跟随时崩溃的对象
the class pointer of the object so here
对象的类指针，所以在这里
we get at least the naked values of the
我们至少得到了
registers yes
注册是
so going further we also get the values
所以走得更远，我们也得到了价值
which have been on top of the stack when
当它们位于堆栈顶部时
the error occurred and we also get the
发生错误，我们也得到了
values near the before and after the
之前和之后的值
instructions where the crash happened
发生坠机的指示
so when the crash happened happens in a
所以当车祸发生在
C++ matter in Lib JVM we can actually we
Lib JVM中的C ++很重要，我们实际上可以
could actually extract that
实际上可以提取
manually but if that happens in
手动，但如果发生在
generated code this may be quite useful
生成的代码，这可能非常有用
to have the actual instructions which
有实际的指示
have been executed because wouldn't be
已被执行，因为不会
easy to extract them it is not if you
容易提取它们，如果不是
wouldn't have a core file yes yes non
没有核心文件是是非
mapping this various back to I just I
映射各种回我
tell you because I know I mean we we are
告诉你，因为我知道我的意思是我们
just analyzing the hot spot error file
只是分析热点错误文件
and we saw that it has this line so it's
我们看到它有这条线，所以
saying that when this hurts whatever I
说，当这伤害了我
was written it couldn't make sense of
被写成没有意义
the register a nine and I just told you
注册九，我刚刚告诉你
why that happens because I know so when
为什么会这样，因为我知道何时
you when you're debugging this crash and
您在调试此崩溃时
you you you're debugging how the hats
你，你在调试帽子
whatever file will be written you will
无论将要写入什么文件
see that it tries to print the value of
看到它尝试打印的值
this object and then crashes a second
该对象然后崩溃
time and then it prints this this value
时间，然后打印此值
I think this West Java 9 actually we can
我认为这个西Java 9实际上可以
just look it up should be here on top of
只是查找它应该在这里
the I don't see it here but it was Java
我在这里看不到，但是是Java
9 I just used a debug build of Java 9
9我刚刚使用了Java 9的调试版本
for it but it would also happen in Java
为此，但它也会在Java中发生
8 because if you write to address 99
8，因为如果您写入地址99
with unsafe you crash in every average
不安全的情况下，您的平均崩溃率
ever version okay so let's continue
曾经的版本还可以，所以让我们继续
we were the instructions and even if you
我们是指示，即使您
have only this hex term of the
只有这个十六进制的
instructions you could use gdb or object
您可以使用gdb或对象的说明
dump or online or SEM disassembler
转储或在线或SEM拆装器
something to disassemble this
一些东西可以拆开
instruction and you see actually this
指令，你实际上看到了
instruction wrote the content of
指令写的内容
register ax which is was 42 to address
注册是42的地址的斧头
RDX which are the X was 99 okay so we
X的RDX是99，所以我们
saw that the hotspot error file contains
看到热点错误文件包含
a lot of useful and interesting
很多有用和有趣的
information
信息
so sometimes we may want this
所以有时候我们可能想要这个
information without crashing the VM so
信息而不会导致VM崩溃
therefore we can use the J command
因此我们可以使用J命令
utility which comes with your JDK
JDK附带的实用程序
distribution and we can just call J
分布，我们可以叫J
command with the PID of your process of
命令与您的进程的PID
your java process and command vm info
您的Java进程和命令vm信息
and if you generate a so called vm info
如果您生成所谓的vm info
file it doesn't contain all the
文件不包含所有
information of our hot spot error file
我们热点错误文件的信息
when a crash happens because obviously
当发生崩溃时，因为
we're not at the crash but it still
我们不是在崩溃中，但它仍然
contains a lot of useful information so
包含很多有用的信息，所以
for example here you can see this this
例如在这里你可以看到这个
was jdk 9 slow debug field it contains
是jdk 9包含的慢调试字段
the command line it contains the
命令行中包含
hardware
硬件
it contains heap addresses and a lot of
它包含堆地址和很多
other useful stuff so sometimes when a
其他有用的东西，所以有时当
customer has problems you can just ask
客户有问题可以问一下
him to send you such a info file for him
他要给他发送这样的信息文件
to generate it so generating this info
生成它，因此生成此信息
file suit should be quite safe so for
西装应该很安全
example generating such an info file
生成此类信息文件的示例
doesn't do the register to region
不注册到区域
mapping because as we saw that may be
映射，因为如我们所见
dangerous so it only prints the the pure
危险的，所以它只打印纯
value of of addresses because you don't
地址的值，因为您没有
want to crash the VM just to get the
想要使VM崩溃只是为了获得
information all of it
信息全部
learning virtual machine sorry ok so now
学习虚拟机对不起，所以现在
let's start with a is a real example
让我们从一个真实的例子开始
let's say somebody some of your clients
假设有人您的一些客户
or colleagues shows you this crash file
或同事向您显示此崩溃文件
or this crash and ask you what can you
还是这次崩溃，问你能做什么
say what happened so any idea I mean the
说出发生了什么事，所以我的意思是
audience was happened here so having a
听众发生在这里，所以有一个
look we see that this time we didn't
看起来我们看到这次我们没有
crash in a native code or in the lip
崩溃在本机代码或嘴唇
when the VM request in interpreted code
当VM请求解释代码时
so this lowercase J means it's a Java
所以这个小写的J表示它是Java
method and it's an interpreted method an
方法，它是一种解释方法
uppercase J would mean it was a just in
大写字母J表示这只是一个
time compiler method so we crashed in an
时间编译器方法，因此我们崩溃了
interpreted method which is called crash
解释方法，称为崩溃
because again it's from an example and
因为这又是一个例子
we get the PC segmentation fault
我们得到了PC分割错误
happened this time
这次发生了
we also get another information because
我们还获得了其他信息，因为
we crashed in the just-in-time compiler
我们在即时编译器中崩溃了
so the hotspot error file so this is the
所以热点错误文件，这是
content of the hotspot error file a
热点错误文件的内容
summary I left out some of the parts
总结我省略了一些部分
which we know already so this time the
我们已经知道了，所以这次
hot so terrify also contains the the
热所以吓人还包含
template of the bytecode in which the
字节码的模板，其中
interpreter cache crashed so the hotspot
解释器缓存崩溃，因此热点
has a so-called template interpreter
有一个所谓的模板解释器
which means that it generates assembly
这意味着它会产生装配
for each Java bytecode and then it calls
对于每个Java字节码，然后调用
them one after another and executes you
他们一个接一个地执行着你
know byte codes and this time we crashed
知道字节码，这一次我们崩溃了
in the error length byte code and the
在错误长度字节码和
hotspot error fire contains the
热点错误火包含
generated code for for this error length
为此错误长度生成的代码
byte code and we can see the address at
字节码，我们可以在下面看到地址
which we crashed and we see the
我们坠毁了，我们看到了
instruction at which request so this is
这是在哪个请求的说明
the instruction where we crashed we see
崩溃的指令，我们看到了
the register area X contains the strange
寄存器区X包含奇数
value batbabe so this is a so-called eye
值蝙蝠宝宝，所以这就是所谓的眼睛
catcher which is used throughout often
经常使用的捕手
use throughout the hotspot 2 to zero out
在整个热点2使用零
memory or to flex some values which are
记忆或显示一些值
illegal so if you see such values
非法的，所以如果你看到这样的价值观
you can search over the code and see
您可以搜索代码并查看
where these values are written and this
这些值写在哪里
may give you an idea why this crash
可能会让您知道为什么此崩溃
happened and here we are actually moving
发生了，我们实际上正在移动
the value of ax to this address and an
该地址的ax值和
entry crash so let's take a look how I
入口崩溃，让我们看看我
have provoked this error how I how I
引发了这个错误
managed to bring the VM in a state where
设法使虚拟机处于以下状态
it crashed in the interpreter so this is
它在解释器中崩溃了，所以这是
a very simple program called crash int
一个非常简单的程序，称为crash int
it has a it contains an integer array
它有一个它包含一个整数数组
and you have a crash function which just
你有一个崩溃功能
returns the length of this array and
返回此数组的长度，然后
again then we create a crash into object
再一次，我们创建一个崩溃到对象
we use unsafe to put some this this bad
我们用不安全的方法来放一些这种不好的东西
paid value at the address of this object
该对象地址处的支付价值
with unsafe so again this is something
不安全，所以这又是
you shouldn't do it's just for the sake
你不应该只是为了缘故
of example and then we call crash so
的例子，然后我们称崩溃
this is the memory layout of our crash
这是我们崩溃的内存布局
into object in the heap so it contains
放入堆中的对象，因此包含
the object header which has a pointer to
具有指向的指针的对象标头
the class or object in the mark word and
标记词中的类或对象，以及
then the actual data itself so in this
然后是实际数据本身
case the data is just a reference to an
如果数据只是对
integer array and then somewhere another
整数数组，然后在另一个地方
place in the heap we have the integer
放在堆中，我们有整数
error itself again the integer array has
再次错误本身整数数组有
object header then it has a length field
对象标头，然后有一个长度字段
and it's an integer area of length one
这是长度为1的整数区域
so it contains one integer so when we
所以它包含一个整数，所以当我们
write this value bad pipe into the I to
将这个值错误的管道写入I
the at offset 12 of our current object
当前对象的偏移量12
we will overwrite this reference to the
我们将覆盖对
integer array and this will point
整数数组，这将指向
somewhere to nowhere so when we then
某个地方到无处，所以当我们
actually execute our crash in function
实际执行功能崩溃
so this is the bytecode of our crash in
所以这是我们崩溃的字节码
function which you can get by running
您可以通过运行获得的功能
Java P on the class you see that it
Java P在类上您会看到它
actually does a load so this loads this
实际上会加载，因此加载此
then gets a get field for for pushing
然后获得推动的获取领域
the integer area onto the stack and any
堆栈上的整数区域以及任何
cost error wailings and error legs of
成本错误哭声和错误分支
course wants to access the length field
当然要访问长度字段
of this object so this is what you
这个对象的东西，所以这就是你
actually what we actually saw here this
实际上我们在这里看到的
is offset twelve of this object that
偏移此对象的十二
contains the length but when we were
包含长度，但是当我们
accessing this we were crashing because
访问这个我们崩溃了，因为
we've overwritten this so again this was
我们已经覆盖了这个，所以这再次是
just an example and this example also
只是一个例子，这个例子也
shows you something
给你看东西
very important when analyzing crashes
在分析崩溃时非常重要
because actually we've crashed in the
因为实际上我们已经坠毁了
interpreter in an interpreted method but
解释器中的解释器方法，但
this was wasn't an error in interpreter
这不是解释器中的错误
the interpreter what works just fine if
解释器什么工作很好，如果
you have for example jane i code
你有例如简我的代码
actually i've actually simulated j'ni
实际上我实际上已经模拟了j'ni
code with unsafe here so if you have J&amp;I
代码不安全，因此如果您有J＆I
code for example and pollute your heap
例如代码并污染您的堆
or do some bad things in your heap
或者在你的堆里做一些坏事
everything can happen so we've just
一切都会发生，所以我们只是
corrupted our object in the heap and
破坏了堆中的对象，并且
then we finally crashed in the
然后我们终于坠毁了
interpreter so this is something you
口译员，这就是你
have to keep in mind the cost of your
必须记住您的成本
object is not always related to the
对象并不总是与
place where you really crash and this
你真正崩溃的地方
makes finding errors very tricky
使得发现错误非常棘手
sometimes okay so I will come now to a
有时还可以，所以我现在来
real example so a problem which you
真实的例子，那么你的问题
really got from our customer until now
直到现在才真正从我们的客户那里得到
we only had two examples to show you how
我们只有两个例子向您展示
everything actually works so we got such
一切实际上都有效，所以我们得到了
a message from a customer that he gets
来自客户的消息，他得到了
out of memory errors out of memory meta
内存不足错误内存不足元
space this was all we received in error
空间，这是我们收到的所有错误信息
message so there is one option you can
信息，因此您可以选择一种
use so if the program at the customer
如果客户使用该程序，则使用
stops anyway because of an exception you
还是因为异常而停止
can try to use this xx crash on out of
可以尝试使用xx崩溃
memory error so in this case the VM will
内存错误，因此在这种情况下，VM将
not only exit with an with an exception
不仅退出，而且有例外
but it will at the same time produce a
但它会同时产生一个
complete hotspot error file and a core
完整的热点错误文件和核心
file we ask the customer to do this and
文件，我们要求客户做到这一点，
he sent us that
他发给我们
generated hotspot error file and the
生成的热点错误文件和
corresponding code file soon this
对应的代码文件很快这个
happened in Java 8
发生在Java 8中
the problem is in Java 8 but I've
问题是在Java 8中，但我已经
analyzed it with Java 9 metastasis
用Java 9转移对其进行了分析
already in Java 8 so prom cane was
已经在Java 8中，所以舞会甘蔗是
removed in Java 8 and replaced by meta
在Java 8中删除并由meta代替
space so this is Java 8 upwards okay so
空间，这是Java 8向上的状态，所以
how does this look like okay this is not
看起来怎么样，这不是
the hot spot error fry from the customer
来自客户的热点错误提示
I cannot show you this but I've done a
我不能告诉你这个，但我已经做了
reproducer which that's exactly the same
完全相同的复制器
thing what happened in the customer side
发生在客户端的事情
and I will show you that at the end of
我会告诉你
the talk okay so you can see that the
谈话还可以，所以您可以看到
program was calling define class it has
程序正在调用它具有的定义类
a class loader classifier parser then
然后是一个类加载器分类器解析器
actually constant pool allocate it run
实际上恒定池分配它运行
into the into the error so this doesn't
进入错误，所以这不会
look weird I mean Java program should
看起来很奇怪，我的意思是Java程序应该
load classes and allocate constant pools
加载类并分配常量池
and so on so another part of the hotspot
等等，热点的另一部分
error file which I haven't which I
我没有的错误文件
haven't shown you before it's the event
在事件发生之前没有向您显示
section so the hotspot error file also
部分，因此热点错误文件也
has a section which records important
有一个记录重要的部分
events which happen during execution and
执行期间发生的事件以及
you can see that before the crash
您可以在崩溃之前看到
happened
发生了
the problem was loading a custom class
问题是加载自定义类
loader and at the end it executed a
加载程序，最后执行
collection a meta space collection
收集元空间
because it obviously ran out of space
因为它显然空间不足
and you see that the meta space
你会看到元空间
collection tried very hard to free
馆藏非常免费
memory but it couldn't succeed so that's
内存，但无法成功，所以
actually the cause of the of the error
实际上是错误原因
so with this information we cannot get
所以有了这些信息我们就无法获得
any further but there are other useful
任何进一步，但还有其他有用的
tools for example serviceability agent
维修性代理等工具
which you can use to inspect the core
您可以用来检查核心
so we also got the core file and we used
所以我们也得到了核心文件
the hotspot debugger with Java hotspot
Java热点的热点调试器
debugger of Java 9 the serviceability
Java 9调试器的可维护性
tool to analyze this core file and the
工具来分析此核心文件和
hotspot debugger has a class browser
热点调试器具有类浏览器
which allows you to look for all the
这使您可以查找所有
classes all the active loaded classes in
将所有活动的加载类分类
a core file when the VM crashed and when
VM崩溃以及何时崩溃
you look for these classes for in a in a
您在一个中寻找这些类
package showing this this example quarks
显示此示例的包夸克
Simonis we see that we actually have
西蒙尼斯（Simonis）我们看到我们实际上有
this custom class loader which was
这个自定义类加载器
loaded before the crash and we have two
崩溃前加载，我们有两个
versions of the same class so that's
同一类的版本，因此
actually also not unusual because you
其实也不罕见，因为你
know in Java every class loader can has
用Java知道每个类加载器都可以拥有
its own version of a class so when you
它自己的类版本，所以当您
have a custom class loader it's possible
有一个自定义的类加载器，这是可能的
it has is version of crash out of memory
它是内存崩溃的版本
and the same time the application class
同时应用程序类
table could have floated this class
桌子本可以上课
before so two two versions of a class
之前有一个类的两个两个版本
it's actually not bad that shouldn't
其实不应该不坏
fill up the meta space so we can dig
填补元空间，以便我们可以挖掘
further in the hotspot error file and it
进一步在热点错误文件中
also contains the last exceptions which
还包含最后一个例外
was thrown by the virtual machine the
被虚拟机扔了
last ten exceptions before the VM
虚拟机之前的最后十个异常
crashed and here we see an interesting
坠毁，在这里我们看到一个有趣的
thing so before the VM crashed it showed
所以在VM崩溃之前它显示了
a linkage error exception and this
链接错误异常
linkage exception was thrown by our
链接异常由我们抛出
custom class loader and it says attempt
自定义类加载器，它表示尝试
to placate class definition for name for
为名称定义类定义
our class name so obviously there were a
我们的班级名称很明显
lot of the appliques last definitions
许多贴花的最后定义
happening and of course one class order
发生，当然是一类命令
can only have one class one version of a
只能有一个类别的一个版本
class so if it tries to reload the same
类，如果它尝试重新加载相同的
class it it gets this exception but this
类它得到这个异常，但这
exception were obviously handled by the
例外显然是由
application so we didn't saw them but in
应用程序，所以我们没有看到它们，但是在
the end it resulted in an out of memory
最终导致内存不足
in the meta space so still this
在元空间，所以还是这样
shouldn't happen because I mean we
不应该发生，因为我的意思是我们
handle this exception why do we get an
处理这个异常，为什么我们得到一个
out of memory error here so the
内存不足错误在这里，所以
stability agent is actually a very very
稳定剂实际上是非常非常
powerful tool and we cannot only use the
功能强大的工具，我们不仅可以使用
graphical tools which are which come
图形工具
with it we can also use it
有了它我们也可以使用它
programmatically it has an API and it
以编程方式它具有一个API并且它
allows us to inspect all the data
允许我们检查所有数据
structures all the C++ data structures
构造所有C ++数据结构
which the hotspot maintains during its
热点在其维护期间
run time so for example every class
运行时间，例如每个课程
object which you have in Java you know
您在Java中拥有的对象
in Java you can get you can call get
在Java中，您可以获取，可以调用get
class on each object has a corresponding
每个对象上的类都有一个对应的
class with Kay a C++ object in the
凯的一个C ++对象中的类
hotspot and now we can use the
热点，现在我们可以使用
serviceability agent to walk these these
这些的服务性代理商
these these C++ representations of the
这些这些的C ++表示
Java classes in in the core file for
核心文件中的Java类
this we get a so-called class of the
这就是所谓的
data graph object which is all the class
数据图对象是所有类
class loaders in the hotspot then we
热点中的类加载器，那么我们
walk them and for every class loader we
走他们，对于每一个类装载者
query all the C++ class objects in which
查询其中所有的C ++类对象
were active at a time and we print them
一次很活跃，我们将它们打印出来
out to to memory so when we run this
存入内存，所以当我们运行它时
program again this is done with Java 9
再次编程，这是使用Java 9完成的
so we have to add the JDK hotspot agent
所以我们必须添加JDK热点代理
module for Java 8 it's in the tools I
Java 8的模块，它在工具I中
think tooth jar files so if you have a
想想牙罐锉，所以如果你有一个
JDK you don't have to do anything
JDK，您无需执行任何操作
whichever 9 you have to add the module
无论哪个9您都必须添加模块
and also add a lot of exports because
而且还增加了很多出口，因为
unfortunately the API isn't publicly
不幸的是，该API并未公开
exported anymore so if you run this on
导出了，所以如果您在
our core file we will see that we had in
我们的核心文件中，我们将看到
we have a lot of C++ classes for
我们有很多C ++类
actually the two class versions which we
实际上我们有两个类的版本
have in Java and then we run this
使用Java，然后运行
through what count we see we have
通过什么计数我们看到我们有
actually 320 versions so this is
实际上是320个版本，所以这是
obviously not ok because you should only
显然不行，因为您应该只
have one C++ class representation for
具有一个C ++类表示
every Java
每个JAVA
in the heap so with all this information
所有这些信息
we were able to reproduce the problem
我们能够重现问题
and this is actually the reproduced er
这实际上是转载人
which I also used for this presentation
我也在这个演讲中使用了
so what we actually do is we get the
所以我们实际上要做的是
byte codes of our class we define a
我们类的字节码我们定义一个
known class loader in order to redefine
已知的类加载器以重新定义
the defined class method the class order
定义的类方法的类顺序
which is protected and then in the loop
受保护，然后进入循环
we rapidly define the same class so this
我们迅速定义了相同的类，因此
will succeed the first time and after
将在第一次和之后成功
the first time we will obviously get
第一次我们显然会得到
linkage errors which we catch and when
我们捕获的链接错误以及何时发生
we do that in a loop we can reproduce
我们可以循环进行复制
this problem and find the memory leak so
这个问题，发现内存泄漏，所以
this was a day 1 problem of the meta
这是meta的第一天问题
space change which was introduced in
引入的空间变化
Java 8 obviously never nobody did this
Java 8显然从来没有人这样做
before catching linkage errors so our
在发现链接错误之前，我们
customer for some reason did this and
客户出于某种原因这样做了，
then he run into this problem so I fixed
然后他遇到了这个问题，所以我解决了
this like in February 2017 just in time
就像2017年2月一样
for Java 9 okay so let's come to the
Java 9好了，让我们来看一下
next example
下一个例子
so I have a look at this hot spot error
所以我来看看这个热点错误
file this time we crashed in the lip JVM
这次我们在lip JVM中崩溃了
in massive code generate array copy if
在海量代码中生成数组副本，如果
you're not familiar with shorts what
你对短裤不熟悉
this doesn't tell you anything but you
这什么都没告诉你，但是你
see it generated a core file a hotspot
看到它生成了一个核心文件热点
error file and this time cert file has
错误文件，这次证书文件有
been generated so called replay file so
生成了所谓的重播文件
this is interesting because it means
这很有趣，因为这意味着
this happened to this crash happened
这次崩溃发生了
during compilation of JIT compilation
在JIT编译期间
and we can see this in the house word
我们可以在房子里看到这个
error file so we see the command line of
错误文件，因此我们看到了
the program and we see that the current
该程序，我们看到当前
threat where the crash happened was the
坠机发生的威胁是
C 2 compiler threat we also see that the
C 2编译器的威胁我们还看到
crash happened to read the compilation
崩溃发生时读取了汇编
of a crash method and then we get the
崩溃方法，然后我们得到
stack trace and see that
堆栈跟踪并看到
happened in a method called generate era
发生在一种称为“生成时代”的方法中
coffee so obviously again we compile a
咖啡，所以很明显，我们再次编译了
array copy system every copy method and
阵列复制系统的每种复制方法和
while we were compiling that one
当我们编译那个
compiler crashed for some reason so
编译器由于某种原因而崩溃，因此
where are we here now we crashed in the
我们现在在哪里，我们坠毁了
c2 compiler in in C++ code not in
C2编译器中的C ++代码不在
generated code but in C plus per call of
生成的代码，但每次调用C加上
the c2 should come compile the sweat so
C2应该来编译汗水，所以
now we can use the replay compiles and
现在我们可以使用重播编译和
replay data file option of Java feed in
Java feed中的重放数据文件选项
this replay file to reproduce the
此重播文件可重现
problem but sad enough when we try to
问题，但是当我们尝试
reproduce the problem the crash doesn't
重现崩溃没有的问题
happen so any idea why it didn't happen
发生，所以任何想法为什么没有发生
so if you look carefully at the hot spot
所以如果你仔细看热点
error file you may remember that it's a
错误文件，您可能还记得它是一个
command line use the option called
命令行使用称为
xx- to escape analysis so the program is
xx-逃脱分析，所以程序是
running without escape analysis when it
运行时没有转义分析
crashed so if you want to reproduce the
崩溃了，所以如果您想重现
problem we obviously have to use the
问题，我们显然必须使用
exactly same command line options
完全相同的命令行选项
because otherwise other code will be
因为否则其他代码将是
generated other cost paths will be taken
产生的其他成本路径
doesn't mean we can reproduce the
并不意味着我们可以复制
problem so that's why the command line
问题，这就是为什么命令行
parameters in hotspot error file are
热点错误文件中的参数是
useful for reproducing the problem so
对于重现问题很有用
when we use the exactly same options on
当我们在上使用完全相同的选项时
the command line now with our replay
现在在命令行重播
file you see we can easily reproduce the
您看到的文件可以很容易地复制
problem
问题
so obviously this means we need the same
所以很明显，这意味着我们需要相同的
classes on the class path as the
类路径上的类作为
customer so you can only do this if you
客户，因此只有在您
have the same version of the program to
具有与该程序相同的版本
the customer has and now that we can
客户拥有了，现在我们可以
reproduce the problem with this replay
重播此重播问题
file it is very easy to use other native
文件，使用其他本机非常容易
debugger like gdb for example place a
例如gdb的调试器放置一个
breakpoint into the offending method and
断点到冒犯的方法和
run the program and see what happens so
运行程序，看看会发生什么
here again I cheated a little bit
我再次在这里作弊
actually I have just just patched the VM
实际上我刚刚修补了虚拟机
such that it crashes in this special for
这样它就崩溃了
this special example but this is
这个特殊的例子，但这是
actually how it also happens in a
实际上它如何在
relative there there is a problem in the
相对有一个问题
in the they often are not often but
在他们经常不经常但是
sometimes there are problems in the
有时在
indicate compiler which only occur in
指示仅在以下位置出现的编译器
very strange situations you know
你知道很奇怪的情况
profiling is that just-in-time
分析是及时的
compilation is done Tina McGee does
编译完成Tina McGee做
inlining that's profiling and in some
内联这是分析，并在一些
strange situations sometimes there
有时会有奇怪的情况
happens some inlining some optimization
发生一些内联一些优化
which never happened before and the
从来没有发生过的
compiler and enter in the compilation
编译器并输入编译
crashes and then it's very useful to
崩溃，然后对
have this replay file because this
有这个重播文件，因为
replay file allows you to compile a
重播文件允许您编译
message in exactly the same way which
消息以完全相同的方式
happens when the crash was recurring so
崩溃发生时会发生，所以
this time what what what have I added
这次我补充了什么
here I actually say that when we compile
我实际上是说，当我们编译时
an array copy a generic copy method and
数组复制，通用复制方法和
the type of the destination array is
目标数组的类型是
crash in the class X or crash 5 in the
在X类中崩溃或在X中崩溃5
class X or crash 6 in the class X then
X级或X级崩溃6
we will just just crash so looking at
我们只会崩溃，所以看着
the program which we used we have a
我们使用的程序有一个
crack class crash 5 we have in across
破解类崩溃5
this x and y we have the crash method we
这个x和y我们有崩溃方法
just cause array copy it takes a source
只是导致数组复制需要一个源
object and copies that into a
对象并将其复制到
destination array of type X so that's if
X类型的目标数组，如果
this happens here we can provoke the
这种情况在这里我们可以引起
crash and then we call this 20,000 times
崩溃，然后我们称之为20,000次
to warm up the JIT compiler and compile
预热JIT编译器并进行编译
the message so we use this method to
消息，所以我们使用这种方法
provoke the problem
惹出问题
for some reason the slides are okay so
由于某种原因，幻灯片还可以，所以
now ii take let's see what you have
现在我来看看你有什么
learned until now we have a similar
学会到现在为止，我们有一个类似的
crash again we crash at the same exactly
再次崩溃，我们完全一样崩溃
same location and we have a replay file
相同的位置，我们有一个重播文件
so this time we are smart enough to use
所以这次我们足够聪明
the same command line options which are
相同的命令行选项
in the hotspot error file and we want to
在热点错误文件中，我们想要
reproduce the problem but this time we
重现问题，但是这次我们
get another error we actually cannot
遇到另一个我们实际上无法解决的错误
reproduce the problem we get an error
重现问题，我们得到一个错误
while replaying the compilation there's
在重放编辑内容的同时
a strange sorry the strange error
一个奇怪的对不起奇怪的错误
message saying java.lang class not i
消息说java.lang类不是我
found lambda form goodness that handled
发现可以处理的lambda形式善良
something like this so what does this
像这样的东西怎么办
mean well during forum s it handles and
在论坛处理期间表示很好
invoke dynamic that the VM generate
调用虚拟机生成的动态
dynamically generates bytecode for
动态生成字节码
helper classes and these classes are
辅助类，这些类是
generated dynamically at runtime they
它们在运行时动态生成
are not in in your class files in your
不在您的班级文件中
application class files so this time we
应用程序类文件，所以这次我们
want it to reproduce our compilation but
希望它重现我们的编译，但
not all the classes which were active at
并非所有活跃于
the time when the problem happened are
问题发生的时间是
available to the VM so we get this error
可用于VM，因此我们会收到此错误
but as we saw before our example didn't
但是正如我们之前看到的那样
use lambdas so maybe this is not
使用lambdas，所以也许这不是
important and often these methods are
重要，这些方法通常是
not really required so we have the
并不是真正需要的，所以我们有
hotspot offers an additional option
热点提供了额外的选择
called replay ignite reply ignore
称为重播点燃回复忽略
initialization errors and you can use
初始化错误，您可以使用
that one to ignore these errors so we
那一个忽略这些错误，所以我们
see the errors are then ignored but we
看到错误然后被忽略，但是我们
still cannot reproduce our our problem
仍然无法重现我们的问题
all the initialization airs are ignored
所有初始化过程都将被忽略
but still the error doesn't happen so to
但仍然不会发生错误，因此
verify that our message actually gets
验证我们的消息确实得到了
compiled we use the print compilation
编译我们使用打印编译
option as you see that this time the
如您所见，这次
crash six crash method which where we
崩溃六种崩溃方法，我们在哪里
crashed
坠毁
we notice from the hotspot error file
我们从热点错误文件中注意到
was indeed compiled compiled but
确实是被狗屎编译，但是
without an error happening so what can
没有错误发生，那么可以
be the problem here so again the hotspot
成为这里的问题，所以再次成为热点
error file may help us here to gain some
错误文件可能会帮助我们在这里获得一些帮助
more information for example here it
更多信息，例如这里
contains and if it shows us that before
包含，如果它表明我们之前
the crash happened
崩溃发生了
we had a class redefinition event so
我们进行了课程重新定义活动
during runtime you know you can use
在运行时，您知道可以使用
class instrumentation and class
班级仪器和班级
redefinition to redefine classes for
重新定义以重新定义类
example a lot of tools monitoring tools
例子很多工具监控工具
for example do this sometimes profilers
例如，有时这样做
they just redefine classes or debuggers
他们只是重新定义类或调试器
can also really find classes so here our
也可以找到课程，所以在这里
class where we crashed was really find
我们坠毁的班级真的找到了
so we see the class was loaded and then
所以我们看到该类已加载，然后
it was redefined so against
它被重新定义，所以反对
serviceability agent may be of use here
适用性代理可能在这里使用
because it allows us to dump the classes
因为它允许我们转储类
in a form which they were active when
以他们活跃的形式
the crash happened form a core file so
崩溃发生在核心文件中
it uses the information in the qualifier
它使用限定符中的信息
to reconstruct the class files and this
重建类文件，这
is actually not a version of the class
实际上不是该类的版本
files you had statically on your disk
静态存储在磁盘上的文件
but the redefined version of the classes
但是类的重新定义版本
which were active at the time when the
在
crash happened which maybe did which may
崩溃发生了，也许做了，可能
be different if free definition happened
如果发生了自由定义则有所不同
and actually this is not not an not an
实际上这不是一个不
easy step because the meta space doesn't
简单的步骤，因为元空间不会
contain your class file one to one
一对一地包含您的课程文件
focused on the disk it contains it
专注于包含它的磁盘
contains the decomposed word data or it
包含分解后的单词数据
has all the information of the constant
拥有常数的所有信息
pool and the byte codes in the methods
池和方法中的字节码
and all in different places but the
和所有在不同的地方，但
serviceability agent can just gather
可维护性代理可以收集
that together and create a very class
一起创造一个非常一流的
part of it of it so we call the Java
它的一部分，所以我们称Java
hotspot debugger command-line interface
热点调试器命令行界面
this time yes
这次是
and this is all openjdk it's all OpenJDK
这就是所有的openjdk，全部是OpenJDK
what I show here so I called the command
我在这里显示的内容，所以我称为命令
build replay jars I quit and I see that
建立重播罐子，我退出了，我看到了
hot sweaty Burger created to jar files
热汗汉堡创建到jar文件
one with the application classes which
一个与应用程序类
were loaded by the application class
由应用程序类加载
loaders and one was the one called bucho
装载机，一种是称为bucho的装载机
which which was which contains all the
哪个包含所有
classes loaded by the boot class loader
引导类加载器加载的类
and now we can try the replay again but
现在我们可以再次尝试重播，但是
this time not with the class is on the
这次不上课了
on the disk on the class pass but with
在类传递的磁盘上，但是
the classes which we have it extracted
我们提取的类
from the core file and when we do that
从核心文件中，当我们这样做时
we see that now we can really reproduce
我们看到，现在我们可以真正复制
the error again which is fine because
再次出现错误，因为
now again we can go into the debugger
现在我们可以进入调试器了
see what happened and hopefully find the
看看发生了什么，希望找到
problem so how I did this this example
问题，所以我怎么做这个例子
it's actually the same example like
其实是一样的例子
before the only difference is that now
之前唯一的区别是现在
the element type of the destination
目标的元素类型
array of the array copies is not X but Y
数组副本的数组不是X而是Y
and you remember we only crashed when
你还记得我们只是在
the destination when the element type
元素类型时的目的地
was X so when we use this program as it
是X，所以当我们使用该程序时
is statically no no error will happen
静态上不会发生任何错误
but here during runtime we used class
但是这里在运行时我们使用了类
redefinition I won't go into details how
重新定义我不会详细介绍
does this be done I just use the
我只是用
instrumentation agent to redefine this
仪表代理重新定义此
class and replace Y by X so when you
并将Y替换为X，所以当您
just use this class it is on the disk
只需使用它在磁盘上的此类
nothing will happen but when you run
什么都不会发生，但是当你跑步时
this program this class a will be
这个课程这个班将是
redefined to have another destination
重新定义为另一个目的地
type not Y but X and then the crash
键入不是Y而是X，然后崩溃
happens so that's why when you used the
发生，所以这就是为什么当您使用
class is extracted from the core file
类是从核心文件中提取的
they had the redefined version of the
他们有重新定义的版本
class and we could reproduce the problem
上课，我们可以重现问题
this is actually a quite common problem
这实际上是一个很普遍的问题
nowadays because many customers in big
如今因为许多大客户
installations that you
您所安装的装置
all kind of instrumentation tools to
各种仪器工具
monitor their tools and the actual code
监控他们的工具和实际代码
which gets executed may be quite
被执行可能是相当
different from the one you your ship to
与您的飞船不同
them and it's it's often very hard then
他们，那通常很难
to reproduce problems in your lab okay
在实验室中重现问题好吗
so again this is where the crash
再次，这是崩溃的地方
happened
发生了
somebody no yeah actually come to a
没有人，实际上是
conclusion No so as I told you before
结论不像我之前告诉你的
crash location crash reason are often
崩溃位置崩溃原因通常是
quite different so if some Jane I caught
完全不同，所以如果我抓到一些简
some bad code changes your your Java
一些错误的代码会改变您的Java
heap you're really out of luck because
堆你真的很走运，因为
you can for example question that you
你可以例如问你
see you could also crashing in the
看到你也可能会崩溃
interpreter as you see or in generated
您所看到或生成的解释器
code so crash location a crash reason is
代码，因此当机位置是当机原因
unfortunately not always related so for
不幸的是，并非总是如此
example if the just-in-time compiler
即时编译器的示例
generates bad code doesn't mean that you
生成错误代码并不意味着您
crash during code generation but during
在代码生成期间崩溃，但在
the execution of a method so then it's
方法的执行，所以它是
very hard this this method may then
这种方法可能很难
corrupt the heap and again later you
破坏堆，后来又
crash a very different location so
撞到一个非常不同的位置，所以
finding the crash reason just was having
找到崩溃原因只是
the crash location is very hard so with
崩溃位置非常困难，因此
this I actually come to the end of my
这实际上我走到了尽头
talk there is a lot of interesting stuff
谈论有很多有趣的东西
which about crash analysis on the web
关于网络崩溃分析的内容
there is some articles in the Java
Java中有一些文章
magazine and roppongi net sink last year
杂志和六本木去年净下沉
which I want to talk about building your
我想谈谈建立您的
own Java debugging tools with
自己的Java调试工具
serviceability agent and instrumentation
适用性代理和仪器
and stuff like that the last thing I
像这样的东西我最后一件事
wanted to point out that serviceability
想指出可维护性
agent was actually introduced 2001
代理实际上是在2001年推出的
already you know by a paper of Kenneth
你已经知道肯尼思的论文
Russell and last buck so this is a very
罗素和最后的钱，所以这是一个非常
old technology
旧技术
and unfortunately it's still not
不幸的是，它仍然没有
officially supported and it breaks from
官方支持，它从
time to time because it really has to
有时，因为它确实必须
always keep the Java implementation at
始终将Java实现保持在
the hot spot implementation and sync but
热点实现和同步，但是
nevertheless if you want to dig into the
不过，如果您想深入了解
implementation details of hot spot it's
热点的实现细节
it's it's a tool I can really advise you
这是我可以真正为您提供建议的工具
to use so that's it here once again the
使用，就在这里再次
slides and I think we run out of time
幻灯片，我认为我们已经没时间了
but if there are quick questions I can
但是如果有快速问题，我可以
try to answer thanks a lot
尝试回答非常感谢
[Applause]
[掌声]